SWETHA KRISHNAN

LinkedIn♦ GitHub Brampton, ON L7A1Y8

(+1) 4376613451 \diamond swethakrishnan7399@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Skilled front-end developer with more than 2 years of experience in maintaining and building web pages. Eager to take on a challenging role in a fast-paced environment where I can leverage my expertise to further develop and enhance my portfolio.

EXPERIENCE

Front-End Devloper, Growth Cx Private Limited - Kochi, India

Feb 2021- May 2023

- Worked as a part of a team, Developed an SEO application using React while managing the state through redux Developed front-end user experience using React TypeScript, Ant Design, Redux, Tailwind CSS, React Router DOM
- Collaborated with design and development teams to create visually stunning and user-friendly websites using HTML, CSS, WordPress, and JavaScript.
- Implemented responsive web design techniques to ensure optimal user experience across different devices and screen sizes.
- Consistently delivered high-quality results, leveraging strong problem-solving skills and a deep understanding of various technologies to meet project goals and deadlines.
- Conducted code reviews and implemented best practices to ensure high-quality and maintainable code.
- Worked closely with clients to understand their requirements and provided technical expertise during project meetings.
- Contributed to the development of five projects, resulting in an average of 60% increase in overall customer satisfaction.
- Maintained and managed repositories on GitHub for multiple projects, fostering efficient collaboration within a Linux-based environment.
- Documented technical workflows and knowledge to educate newly hired employees.

Technical Intern, Tillotoma Foundation - Remote

Oct 2020- Feb 2021

- Assisted in the development and maintenance of client websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Participated in team meetings and contributed ideas for enhancing user experience and optimizing website performance.
- Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements.

EDUCATION

Federal Institute of Science And Technology

Bachelor of Technology

Electrical and Electronics Engineering

Aug 2016 - Sep 2020 CGPA: 7.11

PROJECTS

Suitejar - Web Application

Feb 2021- May 2023

- Developed a Dynamic web application (https://suitejar.com/) for growth.cx using React while managing the state through redux.
- •Used Ant Design tables, alerts, buttons, date picker, tooltips, and tabs for ease of development.
- Implemented Firebase authentication for secure user authentication and provided email and password accounts, Google, and Facebook sign-up options.
- Implemented user plans free, lite, plus, pro, and used stripe for payment.
- closely monitored the website, fixed user issues and improved the website's overall performance.

Technologies: React js, TypeScript, Ant Design, Redux toolkit, Tailwind CSS, Firebase Authentication

MixRank - Web Application

Dec 2022- Mar 2023

- Developed a WordPress website (https://mixrank.com/) with custom template blocks where the client can update the website's information themself without a developer's help.
- Implemented Tailwind CSS for better styling and ease of customization and added JavaScript animation to improve user experience.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, WordPress, PHP, Tailwind CSS

Nintriva - Web Application

Sept 2022- Nov 2022

- Developed a WordPress website (https://nintriva.com/) for client.
- Implemented Tailwind CSS for better styling and ease of customization and added JavaScript animation to improve user experience.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, WordPress, PHP, Tailwind CSS

SKILLS

- Proficient in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
- Strong knowledge of front-end frameworks (React, Vue.js)
- Responsive web design and development
- Cross-browser compatibility
- Version control (Git)
- Web performance optimization
- Familiarity with back-end technologies (Node.js, Express, MongoDB, SQL)
- Problem-solving and debugging skills
- Excellent collaboration and communication skills
- Strong knowlege on CSS Framewoks (Bootstrap, Ant Design, Tailwind, Material UI)